<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://floridafoodfestival.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://floridafoodfestival.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-11-23T01:59:33+00:00</updated><id>https://floridafoodfestival.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Florida Food Festival - A Celebration of Florida’s Culinary Delights</title><subtitle>Join us for the annual Florida Food Festival, showcasing the finest cuisine,  local produce, and culinary talent that Florida has to offer.</subtitle><author><name>Florida Food Festival Team</name></author><entry><title type="html">Madison County Pecan Pie Bars</title><link href="https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/06/04/madison-county-pecan-pie-bars/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Madison County Pecan Pie Bars" /><published>2025-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/06/04/madison-county-pecan-pie-bars</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/06/04/madison-county-pecan-pie-bars/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="madison-county-pecan-pie-bars">Madison County Pecan Pie Bars</h1>

<h2 id="a-north-florida-sweet-treat">A North Florida Sweet Treat</h2>

<p>These bars have a buttery crust and gooey pecan filling, just like classic pecan pie. Perfect for sharing at gatherings!</p>

<h2 id="pecan-pie-bars-recipe">Pecan Pie Bars Recipe</h2>

<h3 id="ingredients">Ingredients:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>1 cup flour</li>
  <li>1/4 cup sugar</li>
  <li>1/2 cup butter, softened</li>
  <li>2 eggs</li>
  <li>3/4 cup light corn syrup</li>
  <li>1/2 cup brown sugar</li>
  <li>1 tablespoon melted butter</li>
  <li>1 teaspoon vanilla extract</li>
  <li>1 1/2 cups chopped pecans</li>
  <li>Pinch of salt</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="instructions">Instructions:</h3>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Make crust</strong>: Mix flour, sugar, and butter. Press into a greased 8x8-inch pan. Bake at 350°F (175°C) for 15 minutes.</li>
  <li><strong>Make filling</strong>: Whisk eggs, corn syrup, brown sugar, melted butter, vanilla, pecans, and salt.</li>
  <li><strong>Bake</strong>: Pour filling over crust. Bake 25-30 minutes. Cool before cutting.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="variations">Variations</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Add chocolate chips to the filling.</li>
  <li>Use maple syrup instead of corn syrup.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="serving-suggestions">Serving Suggestions</h2>
<p>Serve as dessert or a sweet snack.</p>]]></content><author><name>Florida Food Festival Team</name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Madison County Pecan Pie Bars A North Florida Sweet Treat These bars have a buttery crust and gooey pecan filling, just like classic pecan pie. Perfect for sharing at gatherings! Pecan Pie Bars Recipe Ingredients: 1 cup flour 1/4 cup sugar 1/2 cup butter, softened 2 eggs 3/4 cup light corn syrup 1/2 cup brown sugar 1 tablespoon melted butter 1 teaspoon vanilla extract 1 1/2 cups chopped pecans Pinch of salt Instructions: Make crust: Mix flour, sugar, and butter. Press into a greased 8x8-inch pan. Bake at 350°F (175°C) for 15 minutes. Make filling: Whisk eggs, corn syrup, brown sugar, melted butter, vanilla, pecans, and salt. Bake: Pour filling over crust. Bake 25-30 minutes. Cool before cutting. Variations Add chocolate chips to the filling. Use maple syrup instead of corn syrup. Serving Suggestions Serve as dessert or a sweet snack.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lake City Chicken Pilau (Perloo)</title><link href="https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/06/03/lake-city-chicken-pilau/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lake City Chicken Pilau (Perloo)" /><published>2025-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/06/03/lake-city-chicken-pilau</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/06/03/lake-city-chicken-pilau/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="lake-city-chicken-pilau-perloo">Lake City Chicken Pilau (Perloo)</h1>

<h2 id="a-north-florida-family-favorite">A North Florida Family Favorite</h2>

<p>This one-pot meal features tender chicken, rice, and vegetables simmered in a flavorful broth. A classic from Lake City and beyond!</p>

<h2 id="chicken-pilau-recipe">Chicken Pilau Recipe</h2>

<h3 id="ingredients">Ingredients:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>2 lbs bone-in chicken pieces</li>
  <li>1 onion, chopped</li>
  <li>1 bell pepper, chopped</li>
  <li>2 cups long-grain rice</li>
  <li>4 cups chicken broth</li>
  <li>2 tablespoons butter</li>
  <li>1 teaspoon paprika</li>
  <li>1/2 teaspoon black pepper</li>
  <li>Salt to taste</li>
  <li>Chopped parsley for garnish</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="instructions">Instructions:</h3>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Brown chicken</strong>: In a large pot, brown chicken in butter. Remove and set aside.</li>
  <li><strong>Sauté veggies</strong>: Cook onion and bell pepper until soft.</li>
  <li><strong>Simmer</strong>: Return chicken to pot. Add broth, paprika, pepper, and salt. Simmer 30 minutes.</li>
  <li><strong>Add rice</strong>: Stir in rice. Cover and cook until rice is tender and liquid is absorbed.</li>
  <li><strong>Serve</strong>: Garnish with parsley.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="variations">Variations</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Add smoked sausage or peas.</li>
  <li>Use turkey instead of chicken.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="serving-suggestions">Serving Suggestions</h2>
<p>Serve with hot sauce and a side salad.</p>]]></content><author><name>Florida Food Festival Team</name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lake City Chicken Pilau (Perloo) A North Florida Family Favorite This one-pot meal features tender chicken, rice, and vegetables simmered in a flavorful broth. A classic from Lake City and beyond! Chicken Pilau Recipe Ingredients: 2 lbs bone-in chicken pieces 1 onion, chopped 1 bell pepper, chopped 2 cups long-grain rice 4 cups chicken broth 2 tablespoons butter 1 teaspoon paprika 1/2 teaspoon black pepper Salt to taste Chopped parsley for garnish Instructions: Brown chicken: In a large pot, brown chicken in butter. Remove and set aside. Sauté veggies: Cook onion and bell pepper until soft. Simmer: Return chicken to pot. Add broth, paprika, pepper, and salt. Simmer 30 minutes. Add rice: Stir in rice. Cover and cook until rice is tender and liquid is absorbed. Serve: Garnish with parsley. Variations Add smoked sausage or peas. Use turkey instead of chicken. Serving Suggestions Serve with hot sauce and a side salad.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Suwannee River Collard Greens</title><link href="https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/06/02/suwannee-river-collard-greens/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Suwannee River Collard Greens" /><published>2025-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/06/02/suwannee-river-collard-greens</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/06/02/suwannee-river-collard-greens/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="suwannee-river-collard-greens">Suwannee River Collard Greens</h1>

<h2 id="a-taste-of-north-florida-tradition">A Taste of North Florida Tradition</h2>

<p>These collard greens are simmered with bacon and spices for a rich, savory side dish. A must-have at North Florida gatherings!</p>

<h2 id="collard-greens-recipe">Collard Greens Recipe</h2>

<h3 id="ingredients">Ingredients:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>2 lbs collard greens, washed and chopped</li>
  <li>4 slices bacon, chopped</li>
  <li>1 onion, diced</li>
  <li>2 cloves garlic, minced</li>
  <li>4 cups chicken broth</li>
  <li>1 tablespoon apple cider vinegar</li>
  <li>1 teaspoon sugar</li>
  <li>Salt and pepper</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="instructions">Instructions:</h3>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Cook bacon</strong>: In a large pot, cook bacon until crisp. Remove and set aside.</li>
  <li><strong>Sauté veggies</strong>: Cook onion and garlic in bacon fat until soft.</li>
  <li><strong>Simmer greens</strong>: Add collards, broth, vinegar, sugar, salt, and pepper. Simmer 45 minutes.</li>
  <li><strong>Finish</strong>: Stir in bacon before serving.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="variations">Variations</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Use smoked turkey instead of bacon.</li>
  <li>Add hot sauce for extra kick.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="serving-suggestions">Serving Suggestions</h2>
<p>Serve with cornbread or barbecue.</p>]]></content><author><name>Florida Food Festival Team</name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Suwannee River Collard Greens A Taste of North Florida Tradition These collard greens are simmered with bacon and spices for a rich, savory side dish. A must-have at North Florida gatherings! Collard Greens Recipe Ingredients: 2 lbs collard greens, washed and chopped 4 slices bacon, chopped 1 onion, diced 2 cloves garlic, minced 4 cups chicken broth 1 tablespoon apple cider vinegar 1 teaspoon sugar Salt and pepper Instructions: Cook bacon: In a large pot, cook bacon until crisp. Remove and set aside. Sauté veggies: Cook onion and garlic in bacon fat until soft. Simmer greens: Add collards, broth, vinegar, sugar, salt, and pepper. Simmer 45 minutes. Finish: Stir in bacon before serving. Variations Use smoked turkey instead of bacon. Add hot sauce for extra kick. Serving Suggestions Serve with cornbread or barbecue.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Palatka Datil Pepper Hot Sauce</title><link href="https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/06/01/palatka-datil-pepper-hot-sauce/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Palatka Datil Pepper Hot Sauce" /><published>2025-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/06/01/palatka-datil-pepper-hot-sauce</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/06/01/palatka-datil-pepper-hot-sauce/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="palatka-datil-pepper-hot-sauce">Palatka Datil Pepper Hot Sauce</h1>

<h2 id="a-north-florida-specialty">A North Florida Specialty</h2>

<p>This homemade hot sauce features sweet and spicy datil peppers, a North Florida favorite. Perfect for adding heat to any dish!</p>

<h2 id="datil-pepper-hot-sauce-recipe">Datil Pepper Hot Sauce Recipe</h2>

<h3 id="ingredients">Ingredients:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>10 datil peppers, stemmed</li>
  <li>1/2 cup white vinegar</li>
  <li>1/4 cup water</li>
  <li>2 cloves garlic</li>
  <li>1 teaspoon salt</li>
  <li>1 teaspoon sugar</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="instructions">Instructions:</h3>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Blend</strong>: Combine all ingredients in a blender. Puree until smooth.</li>
  <li><strong>Simmer</strong>: Pour into a saucepan. Simmer 10 minutes.</li>
  <li><strong>Cool &amp; bottle</strong>: Cool, then transfer to a bottle. Refrigerate.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="variations">Variations</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Use habanero peppers if datil are unavailable.</li>
  <li>Add mango for a fruity twist.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="serving-suggestions">Serving Suggestions</h2>
<p>Serve with seafood, chicken, or eggs.</p>]]></content><author><name>Florida Food Festival Team</name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Palatka Datil Pepper Hot Sauce A North Florida Specialty This homemade hot sauce features sweet and spicy datil peppers, a North Florida favorite. Perfect for adding heat to any dish! Datil Pepper Hot Sauce Recipe Ingredients: 10 datil peppers, stemmed 1/2 cup white vinegar 1/4 cup water 2 cloves garlic 1 teaspoon salt 1 teaspoon sugar Instructions: Blend: Combine all ingredients in a blender. Puree until smooth. Simmer: Pour into a saucepan. Simmer 10 minutes. Cool &amp; bottle: Cool, then transfer to a bottle. Refrigerate. Variations Use habanero peppers if datil are unavailable. Add mango for a fruity twist. Serving Suggestions Serve with seafood, chicken, or eggs.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fernandina Beach Shrimp Salad Rolls</title><link href="https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/05/31/fernandina-beach-shrimp-salad-rolls/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fernandina Beach Shrimp Salad Rolls" /><published>2025-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/05/31/fernandina-beach-shrimp-salad-rolls</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/05/31/fernandina-beach-shrimp-salad-rolls/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="fernandina-beach-shrimp-salad-rolls">Fernandina Beach Shrimp Salad Rolls</h1>

<h2 id="a-cool-coastal-lunch">A Cool Coastal Lunch</h2>

<p>These rolls are filled with a creamy shrimp salad, crisp celery, and fresh herbs. A refreshing meal for hot North Florida days.</p>

<h2 id="shrimp-salad-rolls-recipe">Shrimp Salad Rolls Recipe</h2>

<h3 id="ingredients">Ingredients:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>1 lb cooked shrimp, chopped</li>
  <li>1/4 cup mayonnaise</li>
  <li>2 tablespoons lemon juice</li>
  <li>1/4 cup diced celery</li>
  <li>2 tablespoons chopped fresh dill or parsley</li>
  <li>Salt and pepper</li>
  <li>4 split-top rolls</li>
  <li>Lettuce leaves</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="instructions">Instructions:</h3>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Mix salad</strong>: Combine shrimp, mayo, lemon juice, celery, herbs, salt, and pepper.</li>
  <li><strong>Assemble</strong>: Line rolls with lettuce. Fill with shrimp salad.</li>
  <li><strong>Serve</strong>: Serve chilled.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="variations">Variations</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Add diced cucumber or red onion.</li>
  <li>Use Greek yogurt instead of mayo.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="serving-suggestions">Serving Suggestions</h2>
<p>Serve with potato chips or fruit salad.</p>]]></content><author><name>Florida Food Festival Team</name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Fernandina Beach Shrimp Salad Rolls A Cool Coastal Lunch These rolls are filled with a creamy shrimp salad, crisp celery, and fresh herbs. A refreshing meal for hot North Florida days. Shrimp Salad Rolls Recipe Ingredients: 1 lb cooked shrimp, chopped 1/4 cup mayonnaise 2 tablespoons lemon juice 1/4 cup diced celery 2 tablespoons chopped fresh dill or parsley Salt and pepper 4 split-top rolls Lettuce leaves Instructions: Mix salad: Combine shrimp, mayo, lemon juice, celery, herbs, salt, and pepper. Assemble: Line rolls with lettuce. Fill with shrimp salad. Serve: Serve chilled. Variations Add diced cucumber or red onion. Use Greek yogurt instead of mayo. Serving Suggestions Serve with potato chips or fruit salad.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Gainesville Boiled Peanuts</title><link href="https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/05/30/gainesville-boiled-peanuts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gainesville Boiled Peanuts" /><published>2025-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/05/30/gainesville-boiled-peanuts</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/05/30/gainesville-boiled-peanuts/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="gainesville-boiled-peanuts">Gainesville Boiled Peanuts</h1>

<h2 id="a-north-florida-roadside-snack">A North Florida Roadside Snack</h2>

<p>These salty, tender peanuts are a staple at North Florida roadside stands and football games. Easy to make and perfect for sharing!</p>

<h2 id="boiled-peanuts-recipe">Boiled Peanuts Recipe</h2>

<h3 id="ingredients">Ingredients:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>2 lbs raw peanuts, in the shell</li>
  <li>1/2 cup salt</li>
  <li>1 gallon water</li>
  <li>Optional: 2 tablespoons Cajun seasoning</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="instructions">Instructions:</h3>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Boil</strong>: Combine peanuts, salt, water, and seasoning in a large pot. Bring to a boil.</li>
  <li><strong>Simmer</strong>: Cover and simmer 2-3 hours, until peanuts are soft.</li>
  <li><strong>Serve</strong>: Drain and serve warm or at room temperature.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="variations">Variations</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Add garlic cloves or hot peppers for extra flavor.</li>
  <li>Use smoked salt for a twist.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="serving-suggestions">Serving Suggestions</h2>
<p>Serve in paper bags for an authentic touch.</p>]]></content><author><name>Florida Food Festival Team</name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Gainesville Boiled Peanuts A North Florida Roadside Snack These salty, tender peanuts are a staple at North Florida roadside stands and football games. Easy to make and perfect for sharing! Boiled Peanuts Recipe Ingredients: 2 lbs raw peanuts, in the shell 1/2 cup salt 1 gallon water Optional: 2 tablespoons Cajun seasoning Instructions: Boil: Combine peanuts, salt, water, and seasoning in a large pot. Bring to a boil. Simmer: Cover and simmer 2-3 hours, until peanuts are soft. Serve: Drain and serve warm or at room temperature. Variations Add garlic cloves or hot peppers for extra flavor. Use smoked salt for a twist. Serving Suggestions Serve in paper bags for an authentic touch.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Apalachicola Oyster Stew</title><link href="https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/05/29/apalachicola-oyster-stew/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Apalachicola Oyster Stew" /><published>2025-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/05/29/apalachicola-oyster-stew</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/05/29/apalachicola-oyster-stew/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="apalachicola-oyster-stew">Apalachicola Oyster Stew</h1>

<h2 id="a-gulf-coast-classic">A Gulf Coast Classic</h2>

<p>This stew features plump Apalachicola oysters in a creamy, buttery broth. It’s simple, comforting, and full of coastal flavor.</p>

<h2 id="oyster-stew-recipe">Oyster Stew Recipe</h2>

<h3 id="ingredients">Ingredients:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>1 pint fresh oysters (with liquor)</li>
  <li>2 tablespoons butter</li>
  <li>1 small onion, finely chopped</li>
  <li>2 cups whole milk</li>
  <li>1/2 cup heavy cream</li>
  <li>Salt and pepper</li>
  <li>Hot sauce (optional)</li>
  <li>Chopped parsley for garnish</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="instructions">Instructions:</h3>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Sauté onion</strong>: Cook onion in butter until soft.</li>
  <li><strong>Simmer</strong>: Add milk and cream. Heat gently (do not boil).</li>
  <li><strong>Add oysters</strong>: Stir in oysters and their liquor. Cook until edges curl.</li>
  <li><strong>Season &amp; serve</strong>: Season with salt, pepper, and hot sauce. Garnish with parsley.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="variations">Variations</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Add diced potatoes for a heartier stew.</li>
  <li>Use half-and-half instead of cream.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="serving-suggestions">Serving Suggestions</h2>
<p>Serve with oyster crackers or crusty bread.</p>]]></content><author><name>Florida Food Festival Team</name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Apalachicola Oyster Stew A Gulf Coast Classic This stew features plump Apalachicola oysters in a creamy, buttery broth. It’s simple, comforting, and full of coastal flavor. Oyster Stew Recipe Ingredients: 1 pint fresh oysters (with liquor) 2 tablespoons butter 1 small onion, finely chopped 2 cups whole milk 1/2 cup heavy cream Salt and pepper Hot sauce (optional) Chopped parsley for garnish Instructions: Sauté onion: Cook onion in butter until soft. Simmer: Add milk and cream. Heat gently (do not boil). Add oysters: Stir in oysters and their liquor. Cook until edges curl. Season &amp; serve: Season with salt, pepper, and hot sauce. Garnish with parsley. Variations Add diced potatoes for a heartier stew. Use half-and-half instead of cream. Serving Suggestions Serve with oyster crackers or crusty bread.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tallahassee Tomato Pie</title><link href="https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/05/28/tallahassee-tomato-pie/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tallahassee Tomato Pie" /><published>2025-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/05/28/tallahassee-tomato-pie</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/05/28/tallahassee-tomato-pie/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="tallahassee-tomato-pie">Tallahassee Tomato Pie</h1>

<h2 id="a-slice-of-north-florida-summer">A Slice of North Florida Summer</h2>

<p>This savory pie features ripe tomatoes, fresh herbs, and a cheesy filling in a flaky crust. It’s a delicious way to use summer’s best tomatoes.</p>

<h2 id="tomato-pie-recipe">Tomato Pie Recipe</h2>

<h3 id="ingredients">Ingredients:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>1 pie crust (store-bought or homemade)</li>
  <li>3 large ripe tomatoes, sliced</li>
  <li>1/2 cup mayonnaise</li>
  <li>1 cup shredded cheddar cheese</li>
  <li>1/2 cup shredded mozzarella cheese</li>
  <li>1/4 cup chopped fresh basil</li>
  <li>1/4 cup chopped green onions</li>
  <li>Salt and pepper</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="instructions">Instructions:</h3>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Prepare crust</strong>: Pre-bake crust at 375°F (190°C) for 10 minutes.</li>
  <li><strong>Layer</strong>: Arrange tomato slices in crust. Sprinkle with salt, pepper, basil, and green onions.</li>
  <li><strong>Mix &amp; top</strong>: Combine mayo and cheeses. Spread over tomatoes.</li>
  <li><strong>Bake</strong>: Bake at 375°F for 30-35 minutes. Cool slightly before slicing.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="variations">Variations</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Add cooked bacon or ham.</li>
  <li>Use a mix of heirloom tomatoes.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="serving-suggestions">Serving Suggestions</h2>
<p>Serve warm or at room temperature with a green salad.</p>]]></content><author><name>Florida Food Festival Team</name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Tallahassee Tomato Pie A Slice of North Florida Summer This savory pie features ripe tomatoes, fresh herbs, and a cheesy filling in a flaky crust. It’s a delicious way to use summer’s best tomatoes. Tomato Pie Recipe Ingredients: 1 pie crust (store-bought or homemade) 3 large ripe tomatoes, sliced 1/2 cup mayonnaise 1 cup shredded cheddar cheese 1/2 cup shredded mozzarella cheese 1/4 cup chopped fresh basil 1/4 cup chopped green onions Salt and pepper Instructions: Prepare crust: Pre-bake crust at 375°F (190°C) for 10 minutes. Layer: Arrange tomato slices in crust. Sprinkle with salt, pepper, basil, and green onions. Mix &amp; top: Combine mayo and cheeses. Spread over tomatoes. Bake: Bake at 375°F for 30-35 minutes. Cool slightly before slicing. Variations Add cooked bacon or ham. Use a mix of heirloom tomatoes. Serving Suggestions Serve warm or at room temperature with a green salad.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pensacola Smoked Mullet Dip</title><link href="https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/05/27/pensacola-smoked-mullet-dip/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pensacola Smoked Mullet Dip" /><published>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/05/27/pensacola-smoked-mullet-dip</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/05/27/pensacola-smoked-mullet-dip/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="pensacola-smoked-mullet-dip">Pensacola Smoked Mullet Dip</h1>

<h2 id="a-panhandle-party-staple">A Panhandle Party Staple</h2>

<p>This creamy, smoky dip is made with local mullet, mayonnaise, and spices. It’s a must-have at North Florida beach parties and picnics.</p>

<h2 id="smoked-mullet-dip-recipe">Smoked Mullet Dip Recipe</h2>

<h3 id="ingredients">Ingredients:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>1 cup smoked mullet, flaked</li>
  <li>1/2 cup mayonnaise</li>
  <li>2 tablespoons cream cheese, softened</li>
  <li>1 tablespoon lemon juice</li>
  <li>1 tablespoon chopped fresh dill</li>
  <li>1 teaspoon hot sauce</li>
  <li>1/4 cup finely diced celery</li>
  <li>Salt and pepper</li>
  <li>Crackers or celery sticks for serving</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="instructions">Instructions:</h3>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Mix</strong>: Combine all ingredients in a bowl. Mix until smooth.</li>
  <li><strong>Chill</strong>: Refrigerate at least 1 hour.</li>
  <li><strong>Serve</strong>: Serve with crackers or celery sticks.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="variations">Variations</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Use smoked whitefish or trout.</li>
  <li>Add chopped pickles or capers.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="serving-suggestions">Serving Suggestions</h2>
<p>Serve as an appetizer or party dip.</p>]]></content><author><name>Florida Food Festival Team</name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Pensacola Smoked Mullet Dip A Panhandle Party Staple This creamy, smoky dip is made with local mullet, mayonnaise, and spices. It’s a must-have at North Florida beach parties and picnics. Smoked Mullet Dip Recipe Ingredients: 1 cup smoked mullet, flaked 1/2 cup mayonnaise 2 tablespoons cream cheese, softened 1 tablespoon lemon juice 1 tablespoon chopped fresh dill 1 teaspoon hot sauce 1/4 cup finely diced celery Salt and pepper Crackers or celery sticks for serving Instructions: Mix: Combine all ingredients in a bowl. Mix until smooth. Chill: Refrigerate at least 1 hour. Serve: Serve with crackers or celery sticks. Variations Use smoked whitefish or trout. Add chopped pickles or capers. Serving Suggestions Serve as an appetizer or party dip.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jacksonville Mayport Shrimp &amp;amp; Grits</title><link href="https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/05/26/jacksonville-mayport-shrimp-grits/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jacksonville Mayport Shrimp &amp;amp; Grits" /><published>2025-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/05/26/jacksonville-mayport-shrimp-grits</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/05/26/jacksonville-mayport-shrimp-grits/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="jacksonville-mayport-shrimp--grits">Jacksonville Mayport Shrimp &amp; Grits</h1>

<h2 id="a-taste-of-the-first-coast">A Taste of the First Coast</h2>

<p>This dish features plump Mayport shrimp sautéed with garlic and spices, served over creamy, buttery grits. A Jacksonville favorite!</p>

<h2 id="mayport-shrimp--grits-recipe">Mayport Shrimp &amp; Grits Recipe</h2>

<h3 id="ingredients">Ingredients:</h3>
<ul>
  <li>1 lb Mayport or local shrimp, peeled and deveined</li>
  <li>1 cup stone-ground grits</li>
  <li>3 cups water</li>
  <li>1 cup milk</li>
  <li>2 tablespoons butter</li>
  <li>1/2 cup shredded cheddar cheese</li>
  <li>2 cloves garlic, minced</li>
  <li>1/2 teaspoon smoked paprika</li>
  <li>1/4 teaspoon cayenne pepper</li>
  <li>2 tablespoons olive oil</li>
  <li>Salt and pepper</li>
  <li>Chopped scallions for garnish</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="instructions">Instructions:</h3>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Cook grits</strong>: Simmer grits in water and milk until thick. Stir in butter, cheese, salt, and pepper.</li>
  <li><strong>Sauté shrimp</strong>: Cook garlic in oil, add shrimp, paprika, cayenne, salt, and pepper. Sauté until pink.</li>
  <li><strong>Serve</strong>: Spoon shrimp over grits. Garnish with scallions.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="variations">Variations</h2>
<ul>
  <li>Add bacon or sausage to the shrimp.</li>
  <li>Use smoked gouda in the grits.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="serving-suggestions">Serving Suggestions</h2>
<p>Serve with collard greens or cornbread.</p>]]></content><author><name>Florida Food Festival Team</name></author><category term="recipe" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Jacksonville Mayport Shrimp &amp; Grits A Taste of the First Coast This dish features plump Mayport shrimp sautéed with garlic and spices, served over creamy, buttery grits. A Jacksonville favorite! Mayport Shrimp &amp; Grits Recipe Ingredients: 1 lb Mayport or local shrimp, peeled and deveined 1 cup stone-ground grits 3 cups water 1 cup milk 2 tablespoons butter 1/2 cup shredded cheddar cheese 2 cloves garlic, minced 1/2 teaspoon smoked paprika 1/4 teaspoon cayenne pepper 2 tablespoons olive oil Salt and pepper Chopped scallions for garnish Instructions: Cook grits: Simmer grits in water and milk until thick. Stir in butter, cheese, salt, and pepper. Sauté shrimp: Cook garlic in oil, add shrimp, paprika, cayenne, salt, and pepper. Sauté until pink. Serve: Spoon shrimp over grits. Garnish with scallions. Variations Add bacon or sausage to the shrimp. Use smoked gouda in the grits. Serving Suggestions Serve with collard greens or cornbread.]]></summary></entry></feed>