<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://floridafoodfestival.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://floridafoodfestival.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-04-19T20:48:41+00:00</updated><id>https://floridafoodfestival.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Florida Food Festival - A Celebration of Florida’s Culinary Delights</title><subtitle>Join us for the annual Florida Food Festival, showcasing the finest cuisine,  local produce, and culinary talent that Florida has to offer.</subtitle><author><name>Florida Food Festival Team</name></author><entry><title type="html">Celebrate Cinco De Mayo</title><link href="https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/04/18/cinco-de-mayo/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrate Cinco De Mayo" /><published>2025-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/04/18/cinco-de-mayo</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://floridafoodfestival.com/events/2025/04/18/cinco-de-mayo/"><![CDATA[<p>Join us for a vibrant celebration of Mexican culture and cuisine at our Cinco De Mayo festival! For five days, experience the sights, sounds, and flavors of Mexico right here in Florida.</p>

<p>Our Cinco De Mayo celebration transforms the Wild Arctic Plaza into a lively Mexican fiesta featuring colorful decorations, entertaining performances, and delicious authentic cuisine.</p>

<p>This family-friendly event offers something for everyone - from traditional live music and dance performances to a high-energy DJ dance party. Sample a variety of Mexican-inspired dishes and refreshing beverages as part of our Seven Seas Food Festival special offerings.</p>

<p>Don’t miss this opportunity to experience Mexican culture and create unforgettable memories with friends and family!</p>]]></content><author><name>Florida Food Festival Team</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Join us for a vibrant celebration of Mexican culture and cuisine at our Cinco De Mayo festival! For five days, experience the sights, sounds, and flavors of Mexico right here in Florida. Our Cinco De Mayo celebration transforms the Wild Arctic Plaza into a lively Mexican fiesta featuring colorful decorations, entertaining performances, and delicious authentic cuisine. This family-friendly event offers something for everyone - from traditional live music and dance performances to a high-energy DJ dance party. Sample a variety of Mexican-inspired dishes and refreshing beverages as part of our Seven Seas Food Festival special offerings. Don’t miss this opportunity to experience Mexican culture and create unforgettable memories with friends and family!]]></summary></entry></feed>